# 大家好 你看 兄弟送了一些西紅杮哦
Hi everyone! Look! My buddy has given me some tomatoes.
# 這西紅杮好像有點爛啦
The tomatoes seem to be a bit rotten.
# 給了菜葉子
Together with these veggie leaves,
# 給我家的那個鵝一起吃
I'll give them to our geese here.
# 鵝頭都伸出來啦
The geese are already peeping out their heads.
# 快點啦 好吃的
C'mon! Here's some good food.
# 這也不要 (註︰這個「也」和下面的「都」一樣，沒有「再次」的意思，只是強調，英文似乎沒有這說法，所以我改了一下變成問句以增強語氣)
Why don't they want it?
# 菜葉子 你看 有好吃的
Veggie leaves. Look! They're really tasty.
# 不吃菜葉子怎麼行
Good geese should have plenty of veggie leaves.
# 給它們吃它們都不吃
Why aren't they eating at all?
# 我去把它趕過來 可能沒看到
I'm gonna drive them here. Perhaps they can't see the food.
# 它好像 它好像是隻母的 這個
This one, it seems, it seems to be female.
# 抓一個公的來
Let me catch a male.
# 那個 那個 這個 這個
That one, that one! This one, this one!
# 那隻 那隻 那邊那個
That one, that one! That one over there.
# 你看 抓子半天才把它抓到
Look! It took us forever to catch it.
# 這個是公的哦
This is a male, you know
# 不要那麼多公的
I don't need so many males.
# 留一隻公的就行了
One is all what I need.
# 給它菜葉子它都不吃
I give it veggie leaves, but it's not eating at all.
# 好久都沒去過河邊了
It has been a long time since my last trip to the riverside.
# 今天
But today,
# 今天就帶它去
today, I'll going with it,
# 河邊
to the riverside.
# 你看 這個鵝 殺好啦
Look! The goose, has been processed.
# 拿到河邊 這邊來烤哦
I take it to the riverside, and grill it here.
# 就直接這樣烤
It can be grilled right away.
# 把它內臟去一下
Let me remove the guts.
# 把這個 這個 這個鵝肉 要稍微切一下哦
Here, here, the meat here, needs to be sliced a few times.
# 要不然太大塊了 烤不熟
It can never be fully cooked otherwise. It's too big and thick.
# 給它捶一下背
Let me give it a back massage.
# 嗯 好啦
Um! Alright!
# 先去腌 去腌一下哦
I'll marinate, marinate it first.
# 加點 這個料酒
Put some, this is cooking wine.
# 不加那麼多
Not too much
# 加點油
Put some oil.
# 加一點
Put some,
# 這個醬油
this is soy sauce.
# 再加點 鹽
And also some, salt
# 再搞幾塊生薑下去
Let me get a few pieces of ginger as well.
# 生薑
Ginger
# 削下去
Slice it into pieces.
# 好啦 攪拌一下
Alright! Mix it well.
# 好啦 再腌個半小時 把那炭燒出來
Alright! Marinate it for half an hour. I'll light the charcoal first.
# 像這樣子 再腌一下先
It's fine now. Marinate it for a while first.
# 炭燒好來
Let me light the charcoal.
# 你看 剛好這裡
Look! It fits very well.
# 鵝就睡在這裡
I'll let the goose sleep here.
# 彈簧床 很舒服的哦
Spring bed. It's super comfy you know.
# 好啦
Alright!
# 生火
Set the fire.
# 先把火生起來
Let's set the fire first.
# 炭全部一起燒掉
Let me burn all the charcoal.
# 誒好 剛剛好
Aya! Perfect!
# 這火候剛剛好
And the fire is awesome.
# 把它翅肪給卸了
I've chopped off the wings.
# 要不然
Otherwise,
# 拍它擋在那裡 (註︰不明白，照字面翻譯算了)
they might get stuck there.
# 這兩個翅肪第一下來烤
I'll grill these two wings in a while.
# 啊 這樣可以
Ah! It's nice!
# 不要這個啦
I don't need this one anymore.
# 太難烤了
It made things too difficult.
# 鴨爪 (鵝爪) (註︰他這視頻不只一次鴨鵝不分，我尊重海洋哥的澄清吧)
Duck foot (goose foot)
# 把它倒出來
Let it drop it out.
# 中間烤不到
The middle part can't get grilled.
# 嗯 好香啊
Um! It smells really nice!
# 嘗一下熟了沒有
Let me have a try and see if it's done.
# 好香啊
It smells so good!
# 我再割一點下來吃
Let me cut one more piece and have a bite,
# 看熟了沒有
to see if it's done now.
# 嗯
Um!
# 好肥(註︰他之後又說「全是瘦肉」，所以這裡的「肥」應該是指多肉而已，我避用"fat"了)
Meaty!
# 嗯 熟啦
Um! It's done now.
# 我們
Let's,
# 邊拍 邊吃
film while eating.
# 這塊肉你吃一下
Try this piece,
# 看看味道怎麼樣
and see how it tastes.
# 好香啊
It smells really nice!
# 幫你搞個大腿吃
Let me get a leg for you.
# 嗯 這個蠻好吃的哦
Um! This is rather tasty!
# 誒呀 翻掉啦
Eya! It's flipped over.
# 誒呦 呼 想跑
Ayo! Huu! You wanna run away?
# 煮熟的鴨子想跑
How can a cooked duck run away?
# 這個 這個大腿還沒熟
The, the leg needs a bit more time.
# 這個把它卸下來才行
I think I need to chop it off.
# 別跑啦
Don't run away!
# 這大腿
The leg
# 哇 這一塊
Wa! What a nice piece!
# 你看這個肉 這個一坨坨肉 熟啦
Look at this meat, this bunches of meat. It's done now.
# 嗯
Um!
# 好香 (註︰這只是一個驚嘆，簡單的"Nice"似乎更合情景)
Nice!
# 全是瘦肉
There's only lean meat.
# 你看 這個鴨(鵝)腿 (註︰海洋哥又替他澄清了，我配合)
Look! This duck (goose) leg
# 最好吃的這個 肉又多
It tastes the best. And it's meaty too.
# 好啦 今天的視頻到這裡啦
Alright! The video ends here.
# 這個好吃
It's so tasty!
# 拜拜
Bye!
# 好啦
Alright!